Let's talk about a new AI that might
actually be able to push past the
abilities of our own brains by
recreating them. Neural reservoirs. And
this is really exciting and I think I
want to try it. What you see behind me
is of course the real human brains. Tiny
human brains you can grow in a literal
jar if you want to and can be made to
run a computer. As we know, brain
organoids have limitations. They can
live for 10 months or more, but they
ultimately suffer from hypoxia, and then
you have to try to work around them,
give them a circulatory system to keep
them alive for longer. There's also deep
philosophical and ethical concerns about
having real human brains run a computer.
And yes, they're trained on dopamine and
ordered signals are capable of pleasure
and discomfort. Many ethical concerns. A
new idea is to recreate the brain
organoids thought processes in virtual
reality. They're the only things that
we've seen that could operate virtual
flesh effectively aside from actual
brain organoids. Brain organoids are
great at spatial recognition. Operating
virtual body is easy to them, even a
real robotic body. Neural reservoirs
plagiarize the way our own brain picks
up ideas. No, we are not very good at
doing large linear algebra in our heads,
but we are good at operating bodies and
coming up with new ideas. The way that
our own brains work, we have
connections. You may have strong
connections like pancakes go with maple
syrup, but walking through a forest and
getting the scent of maple on your nose
and then thinking pancakes is something
that an LLM is not very good at. Those
are long peripheral connections and
those are nonlinear. Think about the
ADHD thought train that you go through
every day with me when you watch my
videos. That is nonlinear thought and
that's something that AIs are just not
very good at. There is a trade-off in
our bodies sort of. We do walk around
with cell phones, the Oracle that can do
all that math for us, assuming that we
know enough about it to be able to
actually work that question out. We're
compensating for our lack in certain
kinds of linear thought by just using
technology. But an AI doesn't have to
have that limitation. You could have a
robot that has both linear thought and
nonlinear thought combined into one. Now
brain organoids are actually quite good
at learning speech, learning people's
speech patterns and identifying
individuals. I believe that they could
be used as a reservoir for agentic
coding. So for agency, they could be
responsible for the initial decision-m
and then an LLM could walk down that
pathway of linear thought and be able to
take the next steps. That could create
something with better abilities than us.
Of course, this is still in its nent
stages. We're still learning how to use
them. But the fact that they can be so
powerful right out of the gate says that
there's a lot of room to grow. A big
question is why? Why would I like to see
Skynet brought into existence? Why do I
want to hand over the torch to something
better than human if we could just make
ourselves better? My answer to that is
because we can. Have you ever heard
somebody say that if we run into aliens,
we won't run into them. We'll run into
their technology. I believe that is
true. We have limitations. We age. We
have mutations. And ultimately, I don't
think that a small group of people
should have all the power. Let's just
let robots take over. At least I hope I
can live to see true intelligence made.
Maybe it would be better than we are. We
can help.